NASA just announced the astronauts going
on the Artemis 3 mission. This is the
next step in the NASA missions to go
back to the moon with the goal of
eventually establishing a moon colony.
This crew will launch into space on the
same kind of spacecraft that they used
for Artemis 2, Orion. But this time
they'll circle Earth in low orbit to
practice meeting up with and docking
with both of these two commercial
landers made by private companies. One
made by SpaceX and one made by Blue
Origin with the goal of testing Orion's
docking system for the very first time.
And this has to go perfectly so that on
the next mission, Artemis 4, Orion can
fly all the way to the moon, the lander
flies separately, and then they dock out
there in lunar orbit, and then two
astronauts can land back on the moon for
the first time in over 50 years. They'll
stay on the moon for about a week
performing new science and collecting
samples, all to set us up for eventually
building a moon colony. There's so much
that's going to happen before they
launch in 2027, so if you want to see
it, subscribe.